<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870123-0009. </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Air</ENAMEX> Proposes Date
For Talks on Pay-Cut Plan</HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01/23/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> LABOR TEX
AIRLINES (AIR) </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MIAMI</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Airlines</ENAMEX> executives notified union leaders that the carrier wishes to discuss selective wage reductions on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Union representatives who could be reached said they hadn't decided whether they would respond. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> By proposing a meeting date, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> moved one step closer toward reopening current high-cost contract agreements with its unions. </s>
<s> The proposal to meet followed an announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Bakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>'s president, laid out proposals to cut wages selectively an average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX>. </s>
<s> The airline's three major labor unions, whose contracts don't expire until year's end at the earliest, have vowed to resist the cuts. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Nevertheless, one union official said he was intrigued by the brief and polite letter, which was hand-delivered by corporate security officers to the unions. </s>
<s> According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Callahan</ENAMEX>, president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>'s flight attendants union, the past practice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>'s parent, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Houston</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air Corp.</ENAMEX>, has involved confrontation and ultimatums to unions either to accept the carrier's terms or to suffer the consequences -- in this case, perhaps, layoffs. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "Yesterday's performance was a departure," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callahan</ENAMEX> said, citing the invitation to conduct broad negotiations -- and the lack of a deadline imposed by management. </s>
<s> "Frankly, it's a little mystifying." </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870209-0005. </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>
Calls for Mediation
In Its Union Talks
---
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marj Charlier</ENAMEX>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02/09/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> AMR LABOR
AIRLINES (AIR) </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dallas</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" ALT="Amr">Amr corp.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> unit said it has called for federal mediation in its contract talks with unions representing its pilots and flight attendants. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A spokesman for the company said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> officials "felt talks had reached a point where mediation would be helpful." </s>
<s> Negotiations with the pilots have been going on for 11 months; talks with flight attendants began six months ago. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Professional Flight Attendants</ENAMEX>, which represents <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s more than 10,000 flight attendants, called the request for mediation "premature" and characterized it as a bargaining tactic that could lead to a lockout. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patt gibbs</ENAMEX>, president of the association, said talks with the company seemed to be progressing well and the call for mediation came as a surprise. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The major outstanding issue in the negotiations with the flight attendants is a two-tier wage scale, in which recent employees' salaries increase on a different scale than the salaries of employees who have worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">american</ENAMEX> for a longer time. </s>
<s> The union wants to narrow the differences between the new scale and the old one. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The company declined to comment on the negotiations or the outstanding issues. </s>
<s> Representatives for the 5,400-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Pilots Association</ENAMEX> didn't return phone calls. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Under the Federal Railway Labor Act, if the mediator fails to bring the two sides together and the two sides don't agree to binding arbitration, a 30-day cooling-off period follows. </s>
<s> After that, the union can strike or the company can lock the union out. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibbs</ENAMEX> said that in response to the company's move, her union will be "escalating" its "corporate campaign" against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> over the next couple of months. </s>
<s> In a corporate campaign, a union tries to get a company's financiers, investors, directors and other financial partners to pressure the company to meet union demands. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A corporate campaign, she said, appeals to her members because "it is a nice, clean way to take a job action, and our women are hired to be nice." the union has decided not to strike, she said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The union has hired a number of professional consultants in its battle with the company, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Rogers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporate Campaign Inc.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX> labor consultant who developed the strategy at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geo. A. Hormel & Co.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX>, meatpacking plant last year. </s>
<s> That campaign, which included a strike, faltered when the company hired new workers and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Meatpacking Union</ENAMEX> wrested control of the local union from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>' supporters. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870310-0059. </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Temporarily Barred From Buying
More of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> in Additional Blow to Bid
---
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie P.</ENAMEX>                            </HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">03/10/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> TWA U PIE
TENDER OFFERS, MERGERS, ACQUISITIONS (TNM)
AIRLINES (AIR) </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> A federal judge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> issued a temporary restraining order preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trans World Airlines</ENAMEX> from buying additional shares of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir Group Inc.</ENAMEX> </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The order, requested in a suit filed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>, dealt another blow to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>'s bid to buy the company for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52</NUMEX> a share. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>, which reached an agreement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont Aviation Inc.</ENAMEX>, yesterday began a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$69</NUMEX> a share tender offer for all the stock outstanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Winston-Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.C.</ENAMEX>,-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> The proposed transaction has an indicated value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.59 billion</NUMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl C. Icahn</ENAMEX>, chairman of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>, wouldn't say whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> would continue its attempt to take over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> disclosed last week that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> already had become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>'s largest shareholder, with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> stake as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Some Wall Street sources and airline industry analysts said they doubted that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> would press the attempt if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> buys <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> "I don't think (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>) has the wherewithal" to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> combined, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Marckesano</ENAMEX>, a securities analyst at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janney Montgomery Scott Inc.</ENAMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marckesano</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> would need an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5 billion</NUMEX> to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> once the merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> is completed. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>, as expected, yesterday filed a second application with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX> for permission to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> The department last week rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>'s first application as "deficient" because it omitted such important information as the merger's potential impact on competition and pricing. </s>
<s> "It's a serious application," a department official said of the new filing. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Even so, Wall Street and airline industry sources have continued to view <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>'s bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> skeptically, seeing it as a ploy to pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> into buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> That view was supported in a tender-offer document filed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> and in another document filed in court. </s>
<s> The filings gave details of conversations between Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin I. Colodny</ENAMEX>, chairman and chief executive officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> said in the filings that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> first contacted Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colodny</ENAMEX> last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> to discuss the benefits of combining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> -- either by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>'s acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>'s acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> again called Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colodny</ENAMEX>, according to the documents. </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX>, the documents said, told Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colodny</ENAMEX> that a merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> would put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> in a tough competitive position. </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> reportedly said he "couldn't watch that happen." </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> then proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>, or that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> While Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> is known to have approached several investment bankers in the last week, seeking advice on how to proceed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>'s offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>, Wall Street sources say he hasn't retained any investment banking firm in connection with the bid. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Nevertheless, sources close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> weren't willing to claim victory over Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>, even though the tender offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> has begun. </s>
<s> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX> is a tenacious fellow," said a source close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> "He doesn't give up easily and one should never underestimate what he can or will do." </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> couldn't be reached for comment. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Sources familiar with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> said that, so far, the airline is taking a loss on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> shares it bought late last week. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> is understood to have held a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.9%</NUMEX> stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> for nearly a year before increasing its position to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> in recent weeks. </s>
<s> A source close to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> said that the latest stake was bought at prices ranging from about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48.50</NUMEX> a share to more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> a share. </s>
<s> That would indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> has taken a loss of more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> shares. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The drop reduced the market value of the 22 million shares that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX>-led investor group hold in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> by some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 million</NUMEX>. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> stock fell <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.375</NUMEX> to close at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$47.75</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> declined <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">62.5 cents</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$67.625</NUMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Wall Street traders said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> shares fell partly because of market uncertainty about federal regulatory approval for a merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> But sources close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> said they didn't believe there would be any problem obtaining approval for the merger and pointed out that the company plans to complete its tender <COMMENT> Paragraphing Error </COMMENT> </s>
</p>
   Sources close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> conceded that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>
is permitted to buy more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> shares, it certainly has
enough cash, an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900 million</NUMEX>, to do so. Of that
money, about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 million</NUMEX> is committed to the purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USX
Corp.</ENAMEX> shares, in which Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> currently owns an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.4%</NUMEX>
stake.
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> hasn't yet filed documents with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> in connection with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> holding, and it isn't known how much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>'s money is committed to buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> shares. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Separately, in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> filing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> disclosed details of its plans for financing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> acquisition. </s>
<s> The company said it received a letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturers Hanover Trust Co.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> indicating the bank's willingness to provide as much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> for the purchase. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturers Hanover</ENAMEX> also is willing to act as agent to raise the remainder of the funds. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> said it expects to borrow as much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> from banks to complete the acquisition. </s>
<s> It then plans to refinance the bank loans with proceeds from public or private equity and subordinated debt offerings. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The airline also said in the filing that it expects to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>'s headquarters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Winston-Salem</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William R. Howard</ENAMEX>, chairman and chief executive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>, will be elected president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> after the merger is completed. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Lawyers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> are due back in court in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> this morning to determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> can proceed to buy more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> stock. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> has asked the court to issue a preliminary injunction, enjoining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> from buying more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> shares and from interfering with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>'s tender offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> stock. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> argues that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> violated the Hart-Scott-Rodino Act by buying more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> stock without first receiving regulatory approvals. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> also alleges that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> weren't entitled to buy more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>'s stock without first receiving permission from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Department</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A lawyer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icahn</ENAMEX>, in an affidavit, denied that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> has done anything wrong by buying a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> says that it isn't subject to Hart-Scott-Rodino regulations and must only seek approval from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Department</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Lawyers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> said that the voting-trust application they filed with the department <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> allows the airline to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> stock while a separate application to acquire control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> is considered. </s>
<s> Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Houston</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air Corp.</ENAMEX> bought more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.9%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Airlines</ENAMEX> -- which it later acquired entirely -- before the department approved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air</ENAMEX>'s application to create a trust to hold the shares. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870420-0050. </DOCNO>
<HL> (missing headline) </HL>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> UAL LABOR
AIRLINES (AIR)
TENDER OFFERS, MERGERS, ACQUISITIONS (TNM) </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> As senior director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX>, and a member of the executive committee of its board, I am appalled at the inaccuracies and anti-management bias in the Journal's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17</TIMEX> article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ferris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX>'s chief executive officer. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> board is four-square behind Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX>, his management team and his long-range strategy of making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> a more competitive airline by combining it with the premier hotel company and car rental company. </s>
<s> Contrary to what the Journal article suggests, board members have not been dissatisfied with the financial performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin Hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Like Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX>, the directors have been dissatisfied with the earnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> We share his determination to improve them. </s>
<s> But we recognize that fare wars begun by non-union airline competitors have been responsible for a large part of our difficulties. </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hartigan</ENAMEX>, president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>, are taking steps to improve its earnings. </s>
<s> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">First-quarter</TIMEX> financial results of the airline should show a substantial improvement over comparable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> results, raising the prospect of a much better year-over-year financial performance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Contrary to the implication in your article, the fact that the outside directors have employed independent legal and financial counsel in response to the pilots' proposal to purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> does not bespeak a lack of confidence in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> The employment of independent counsel by outside directors is standard procedure in proposed corporate buyout situations. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The Journal's reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s reputed desire to cause the breakup of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> so that he can own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Century Plaza Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> ignores an important fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> does not own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Century Plaza</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Most unfair and inaccurate was the Journal's reference to the case of the "570 newly hired pilots" whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> "tried to fire" because they "refused to cross picket lines." </s>
<s> These are pilots who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> were offered and accepted pre-hiring training with the knowledge they would be expected to fly if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>'s service were to be disrupted by a strike later that year. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> When the pilots' strike occurred, the trainees declined to cross the picket line; thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> declined to hire them. </s>
<s> In litigation that arose out of the strike, a federal district court ruled that the 570 individuals must be hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>, and they have been flying in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> cockpits ever since. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> upheld a circuit court reversal of the district court, and held that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> was not required to hire the 570 pilots. </s>
<s> However, in an effort to let bygones be bygones, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> management declined to take advantage of its court victory, and it retained the 570 pilots with seniority dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> when they actually began flying for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Neither Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferris</ENAMEX> nor the board of directors has any desire to "break" the pilots' union. </s>
<s> If harsh things were said by either side in the heat of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> pilot strike, or since, we regret them, and want to forget them. </s>
<s> We like and admire our pilots, who are the best in the business, and we respect their right to have a strong union. </s>
<s> We are sure that, likewise, they want us to do our best to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> a strong and prosperous employer. </s>
</p>
   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charled F. Luce</ENAMEX>
   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
   ---
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> has a management contract to operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Century Plaza</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> Any acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAL</ENAMEX> wouldn't confer ownership rights. -- Ed. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870602-0139. </DOCNO>
<HL> Letters to the Editor:
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> Isn't 'Bashing' Mediation</HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">06/02/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> COMMODITY NEWS, FARM PRODUCTS (CMD)
BANKS, THRIFT INSTITUTIONS (BNK) </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> I was pleased to see your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>
article, "Farm-Debt Mediation Catches On in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>." </s>
<s> Farm-debt mediation is, indeed, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Farm Belt</ENAMEX> success story in the midst of the most devastating crash in the farm economy since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE" STATUS="OPT">the Great Depression</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> I am compelled, however, to comment on your evaluation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s mediation program. </s>
<s> While <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s program has met some resistance from creditors, it nonetheless has been a solid success. </s>
<s> As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24</TIMEX>, there were 3,864 mediations that either have been completed or were in progress. </s>
<s> Of the 2,939 completed mediations, 1,393 -- or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX> -- resulted in an agreement. </s>
<s> It is clear from these figures that despite the naysayers, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> mediation works. </s>
<s> It helps keep farmers on the land and creditors in business. </s>
<s> Most important, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Minnesota</ENAMEX> found when it evaluated the program last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, mediation has reduced significantly the threat of violence in rural areas. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Moreover, recent data indicate that mediation is a viable alternative to bankruptcy. </s>
<s> An analysis completed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Rural Affairs</ENAMEX> indicates that states with mediation have had proportionately fewer Chapter 12 bankruptcy filings. </s>
<s> Of the six Midwestern states surveyed, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> had the fewest Chapter 12 filings per 1,000 farmers. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> As your article notes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota Legislature</ENAMEX> is considering various amendments to the Mediation Act. </s>
<s> However, the proposed amendments are not the result of "mediation-bashing," as the article suggests. </s>
<s> Rather, they are the result of a growing consensus that mediation works and should be improved in order to ensure it works even better. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The program's record speaks for itself. </s>
<s> It demonstrates that farmers and lenders can work together to solve the challenge created by the continuing crisis in our nation's rural economy. </s>
</p>
   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubert H. Humphrey III</ENAMEX>
   Attorney General
   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION" ALT="Minnesota">State of Minnesota</ENAMEX>
   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870622-0030. </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> to Put Contract Offer
Into Effect; Strike Possible</HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">06/22/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> GE LABOR </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Broadcasting Co.</ENAMEX> told its technicians and news employees union that the network will put into effect next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> its latest contract offer. </s>
<s> Union leaders said the move probably means the union's 2,800 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> members -- about a third of the company's work force -- will strike. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "It looks like we're going to be there on the street, unless there is a miracle," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Krieger</ENAMEX>, a spokesman for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians</ENAMEX>, which last struck <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric Co.</ENAMEX> unit, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The possibility of a strike comes amid growing signs of a strike among members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directors Guild of America</ENAMEX>, whose talks with the three major networks on a contract to replace an agreement expiring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX> appear to be stalling. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, a federal mediator brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> and the union together for the first time since the union's four-year contract expired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> Both sides were deadlocked. </s>
<s> Areas of dispute include use of temporary workers at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, the length of the new contract and use of non-network news services. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870805-0035. </DOCNO>
<HL> Business Brief:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Union Corp.</ENAMEX></HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">08/05/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> WU LABOR </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Union Corp.</ENAMEX> said its subsidiary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Union Telegraph Co.</ENAMEX>, agreed to extend labor contracts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Telegraph Workers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Workers of America</ENAMEX> for three years. </s>
<s> The contracts, signed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> following strikes by the unions, were to expire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 6</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Saddle River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.J.</ENAMEX>-based communications systems company. </s>
<s> The agreement provides for a one-year extension of the existing contracts. </s>
<s> At the end of the first and second years, the company or the unions may choose to renegotiate wages, pensions and health care. </s>
<s> The accord also provides for cost-of-living adjustments in the second and third years. </s>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Telegraph Workers</ENAMEX> union represents 4,400 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Union</ENAMEX> employees around the country. </s>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Workers of America</ENAMEX> represents 300 company employees in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York City</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870917-0001. </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> Plans
New Canadian
Contract Offer
---
Walkout Could Be Settled
By Weekend; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> Talks
With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> Progressing
---
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Lamphier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob M. Schlesinger</ENAMEX>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">09/17/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> F C CANDA LABOR
AUTOS, AUTO PARTS (AUT) </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> Striking auto workers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Corp.</ENAMEX>'s Canadian unit appeared to be making progress in negotiations yesterday, as the company said it planned to make a new contract offer by this morning. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Meanwhile, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dearborn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Motor Co.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Auto Workers</ENAMEX> union continued negotiations into the evening yesterday, but neither side would officially discuss progress. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Early in the day, bargaining committee members had reported to their union locals that a settlement was imminent. </s>
<s> Still, negotiations dragged on. </s>
<s> Late last night union officials were still hoping to announce a settlement by early this morning. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Bieber</ENAMEX> was absent from the talks all day. </s>
<s> The 57-year-old union leader checked into Henry Ford Hospital in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Detroit</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> night for testing because of abdominal pain, one source said. </s>
<s> The tests ruled out any heart problems, and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bieber</ENAMEX> was apparently in "good condition," the source said. </s>
<s> He added that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bieber</ENAMEX>'s hospitalization doesn't affect the pace of negotiations. </s>
<s> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> spokesman would neither confirm nor deny the report. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toronto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert White</ENAMEX>, president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Auto Workers</ENAMEX> union, said he expects the new offer from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Canada Ltd.</ENAMEX> to contain sweetened cost-of-living adjustments for pensioners. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The Canadian union has made inflation-indexed pension payments its top priority in the talks. </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> said negotiators "unlocked the logjam on the main issue" after all-night meetings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and yesterday. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The union struck <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Canada</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> after rejecting a company offer on pension adjustments. </s>
<s> The union said the size of the adjustments was inadequate. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Canada</ENAMEX>'s chief negotiator, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Fisher</ENAMEX>, said yesterday that the two sides had reached "some understandings" on economic issues, including pensions. </s>
<s> "We have a good chance of wrapping something up by the end of the week," he said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> allowed negotiations on local issues to resume yesterday. </s>
<s> About 200 local issues that remain unsettled had been suspended while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> grappled with the pension issue. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> If a settlement comes today or tomorrow, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s 10,000 Canadian workers could vote on a contract this weekend, when the union has scheduled membership meetings for the striking workers. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> said its four Canadian plants could resume production <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> if a new pact is accepted. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A company spokesman said about 2,285 workers remain on layoff at two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> plants as a result of the Canadian strike. </s>
<s> As previously reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> stopped output of Dodge Dynasty and Chrysler New Yorker cars yesterday at its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Belvidere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ill.</ENAMEX>, plant because of a shortage of Canadian-made parts. </s>
<s> Some 1,700 of the plant's 2,900 hourly employees were laid off as a result. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Also, about 585 workers were laid off at a stamping plant near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Detroit</ENAMEX> because the parts they make aren't needed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> during the strike. </s>
<s> That plant normally employs 2,800 hourly workers. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAW</ENAMEX>'s contracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> and the Canadian units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors Corp.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Motor Co.</ENAMEX> expired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> Talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> are on hold pending the outcome of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> talks. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> talks, the two parties turned to economics yesterday in addition to the job-security issue. </s>
<s> Sources said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> expressed willingness to offer some sort of base-wage raise, or annual improvement factor, but it wasn't clear how much or for how many years. </s>
<s> In the previous contract, the company made lump-sum payments instead of base-wage raises in two of the three years. </s>
<s> It offered no base-wage raises in its initial proposal this year. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> On the job-security issue, it is understood that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> agreed not to lay off any workers during the life of the contract except during a major sales plunge. </s>
<s> The company also promised to replace half of all workers leaving the company. </s>
<s> At last report, the two sides were still haggling over details of the job-security plan, while also discussing the wage and benefit package. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The contract expired at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, but the union, citing progress, agreed to an indefinite extension. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX>'s contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> also expired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, but negotiations with the No. 1 auto maker were postponed pending a settlement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> contract doesn't expire until next year. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Yesterday in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> composite trading, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> closed at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42.25</NUMEX>, down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> closed at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$104</NUMEX>, down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">62.5 cents</NUMEX>. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 870929-0034. </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> See Progress
On Resuming Trade Talks</HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">09/29/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> CANDA
MONETARY NEWS, FOREIGN EXCHANGE, TRADE (MON)
TREASURY DEPARTMENT (TRE)
EXECUTIVE (EXE) </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> Secretary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baker</ENAMEX> held a 7 1/2-hour negotiating session with top Canadian officials, and the two sides made progress toward possible resumption of talks on a free-trade pact. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "We have been reviewing all elements of the trade agreement, and we made a lot of progress today," Canadian Trade Minister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Carney</ENAMEX> told reporters. </s>
<s> But she said a decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> on whether to resume the negotiations wouldn't come until after Prime Minister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Mulroney</ENAMEX> and his cabinet have been briefed today. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Trade Representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clayton Yeutter</ENAMEX> said in a statement that the daylong meeting was "a thorough discussion of all the elements involved in the negotiations." </s>
<s> They added, "We are hopeful that this will provide a basis for the negotiations to resume, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> remains prepared to resume negotiations at any time." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> walked out of the talks last week, claiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> had shown insufficient flexibility on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ottawa</ENAMEX>'s main demand for a binding mechanism for settling trade disputes between the two countries. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 871103-0032. </DOCNO>
<HL> Mediator Enters the Talks
Between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Board</ENAMEX>, Union</HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/03/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> LABOR
SECURITIES INDUSTRY (SCR) </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> A federal mediator is trying to reconcile the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> and about 1,300 of its clerical and operations staff members, whose union contract expired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> night. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The mediator has imposed a news blackout on the two sides, so a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Board</ENAMEX> spokesman couldn't comment on the talks. </s>
<s> The spokesman did say that the exchange would be able to function normally in the event of a walkout. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The workers, members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office and Professional Employees International Union Local 153</ENAMEX>, work for the exchange; for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Industry Automation Corp.</ENAMEX>, which operates the exchange's computers and of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Board</ENAMEX> owns two-thirds; and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Futures Exchange</ENAMEX>, a unit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Board</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Officials at the union and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service</ENAMEX> couldn't be reached for comment. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> When the union's previous contract expired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1984</TIMEX>, the union kept working for eight months without a contract until an agreement was reached in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1985</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 871112-0041. </DOCNO>
<HL> International Corporate Report</HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/12/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> EUROP
TENDER OFFERS, MERGERS, ACQUISITIONS (TNM)
FINANCIAL, INSURANCE, MUTUAL FUNDS, ACCOUNTING, LEASING (FIN)
INSURANCE (INS)
BANKS, THRIFT INSTITUTIONS (BNK)
BOND MARKET NEWS (BON)
AUTOS, AUTO PARTS (AUT) </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAYERISCHE MOTOREN WERKE AG</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>, said parent-company sales rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>'s first 10 months, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14.4 billion West German marks</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.66 billion</NUMEX>) from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.3 billion marks</NUMEX> a year earlier. </s>
<s> The auto maker didn't disclose consolidated sales or earnings but predicted a rise in group sales to about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 billion marks</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17.52 billion marks</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody's Investors Service Inc.</ENAMEX> placed the long-term debt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEN NORSKE CREDITBANK</ENAMEX> under review for possible downgrading, following the bank's announcement last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that it may have incurred trading losses of more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">600 million Norwegian kroner</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$94.3 million</NUMEX>) over the past month -- enough to wipe out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> net income -- partly through unauthorized dealing by an individual broker in the bank's own portfolio. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody's</ENAMEX>, which currently rates the long-term debt of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Norway</ENAMEX>'s largest bank double-A-3, said about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> of debt is affected by the review. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEUTSCHE GENOSSENSCHAFTS BANK</ENAMEX> said it intends to acquire a majority stake in the trade union-owned insurance group <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VOLKSFUERSORGE</ENAMEX> through an insurance concern it controls. </s>
<s> The combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volksfuersorge</ENAMEX> and the insurance group <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&V ALLGEMEINE VERSICHERUNGS AG</ENAMEX> would form <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Germany</ENAMEX>'s second-largest retail-insurance concern. </s>
<s> A spokesman for the trade-union holding company said it is likely to sell slightly more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volksfuersorge</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LINDE AG</ENAMEX> said that group sales fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.7%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>'s first nine months, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.56 billion West German marks</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.54 billion</NUMEX>) from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.73 billion marks</NUMEX> a year earlier, but that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> sales are expected to rise as much as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> as the result of several large orders booked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> The machinery maker's earnings this year are likely to be "wholly satisfactory," Chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Meinhardt</ENAMEX> said. </s>
<s> Analysts expect domestic group profit to rise from last year's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">106 million marks</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63.7 million</NUMEX>). </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATIONALE NEDERLANDEN N.V.</ENAMEX> said it expects to reach a definitive agreement "within the next few weeks" to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIDWESTERN UNITED LIFE INSURANCE CO.</ENAMEX>, one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> subsidiaries, to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s largest insurer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRISH LIFE PLC.</ENAMEX> </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">The Netherlands</ENAMEX>' biggest insurance group said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwestern United</ENAMEX> duplicated the operations of one of its other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> units and that the Dutch concern hasn't changed its strategy of increasing its North American presence through expansion of existing subsidiaries and new acquisitions. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 871125-0048. </DOCNO>
<HL> Business Brief:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Satellite Corp.</ENAMEX></HL>
<DD> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/25/87</TIMEX></DD>
<SO> WALL STREET JOURNAL (J)</SO>
<IN> CQ T
TELECOMMUNICATIONS, BROADCASTING, TELEPHONE, TELEGRAPH (TEL) </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Satellite Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, said it submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> a proposal to reduce by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> rates for certain international telecommunication services. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> In exchange for the reductions, customers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Telephone & Telegraph Co.</ENAMEX> would have to commit themselves to using one of two new types of digital satellite services for a 10-year period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comsat</ENAMEX> said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The proposal is part of a multi-year agreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comsat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> that guarantees <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comsat</ENAMEX> a portion of the telephone company's international business in the face of growing competition from fiber-optic cables. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comsat</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and other customers would be able to convert gradually to the new digital service beginning next year, and that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, as much as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83%</NUMEX> of a customer's international circuits could qualify for the price reductions. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Digital service allows telecommunications customers to subdivide satellite circuits to handle more than one message at a time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comsat</ENAMEX> said. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880111-0081 </DOCNO>
<HL> Federal Mediators Expected to Release <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> From Contract Talks </HL>
<AUTHOR> Teri Agins (WSJ Staff) </AUTHOR>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> GOVMT PN LABOR </CO>
<IN> AIR </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Mediation Board</ENAMEX> is expected to release <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am Corp.</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> union from their long-stalled contract negotiations, throwing into question a wage-concession agreement. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The release means both sides will be asked to submit to arbitration; if one of the parties refuses, as is expected, a 30-day cooling off period will go into effect, after which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> are free to strike. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Genoese</ENAMEX>, head of the airline division of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Brotherhood of Teamsters</ENAMEX>, said he was "shocked and surprised" when he heard late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> from negotiator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Wallace</ENAMEX> of the board's plans to release the parties from negotiations. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon EST</TIMEX> today, the mediation board is expected to ask both parties to submit to arbitration. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> As previously reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> had asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Mediation Board</ENAMEX> to declare an impasse in the talks in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX>, sensing progress in its recent negotiations with the unions, asked the board to delay acting on the company's request, a source close to the board said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Also as previously reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> said last week it would make "changes in senior management" in exchange for labor-cost concessions of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180 million</NUMEX> a year for three years from the unions of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan American World Airways</ENAMEX> unit. </s>
<s> The agreement was reached by a coalition of four of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX>'s five unions; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> union was part of that coalition -- but has made it clear recently it did not necessarily go along with the agreement. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> For the past year, the coalition has been trying to force a restructuring of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> and a change in top management. </s>
<s> Negotiations have been held with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William T. Coleman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> director and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> attorney. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX>'s directors are scheduled to meet tomorrow, the deadline set for the union's wage-concession agreement. </s>
<s> It wasn't immediately clear if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>'s release might jeopardize that agreement. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genoese</ENAMEX> said he sent a telegram to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> to announce that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> plan to end their talks with the company. </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genoese</ENAMEX> said he had a "cordial" initial meeting with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, but made no commitment to provide concessions. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "That meeting made it clear to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> are still deadlocked," one source close to the negotiations said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "As far as we're concerned, the company triggered this," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genoese</ENAMEX> said. </s>
<s> "We're not negotiating any more with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> We're in strike procedure now." </s>
<s> The union has already indicated it would not be willing to submit to arbitration. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX> spokesman declined to comment. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>, which represent about 4,500 ticket agents, reservation agents and clerical workers, have been working under a contract that was negotiated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> and scheduled to be renegotiated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> The federal mediation board has rejected several earlier requests by the union to declare the negotiations deadlocked. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Am</ENAMEX>'s pilots union said it is preparing to sign an agreement to deliver concessions to the company today. </s>
<s> A pilot's union spokesman said the leaders plan to take the agreement to their membership for ratification. </s>
<s> He said he didn't know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> action would affect the union's agreement with the company. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880127-0073 </DOCNO>
<HL> Rise in Labor Costs, Wage Agreements Leveled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'87</TIMEX>, After Narrowing for Years </HL>
<AUTHOR> Jeanne Saddler (WSJ Staff) </AUTHOR>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> LABOR </CO>
<IN> ECO EMI </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> The rise in labor costs and wage settlements, which has been narrowing for most of the decade, leveled off last year, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Total compensation costs in private industry, including pay and benefits, rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3%</NUMEX> last year after a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.2%</NUMEX> increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, the department said. </s>
<s> The increase in these costs had been getting smaller each year since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, when they rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.8%</NUMEX>, the same as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Meanwhile, collective bargaining agreements reached last year called for an average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.2%</NUMEX> wage increase in the first year of the contract and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.1%</NUMEX> annually over the life of the pact. </s>
<s> The industries surveyed agreed to the same percentage pay raises when they last reached contract accords, the department said. </s>
<s> Officials said it's the first time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> that current contract settlements didn't provide lower average wage adjustments than the bargaining agreements they replaced. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The wage agreements reached last year also were higher than the average pay rises bargained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, when a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.2%</NUMEX> increase in the first contract year and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8%</NUMEX> annual increase during the life of the settlements were the smallest increases recorded during the 20 years the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> has collected the statistics. </s>
<s> Department officials said this year's higher wage increases don't necessarily indicate a trend. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A tighter labor market in the services sector may be part of the reason the compensation increases have leveled off, officials said. </s>
<s> A tighter labor market would allow employees to demand higher pay and benefits. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> In its report on major collective bargaining agreements, the department said that the average increase was reduced by lump-sum payments, which are one-time payments often made upon a contract's ratification. </s>
<s> The payments often are provided instead of wage increases, but they aren't included in wages and aren't used as a base for future increases. </s>
<s> About half of the workers covered by big labor contracts last year received these payments. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Better-than-average wage settlements for construction industry workers -- specifically those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Atlantic</ENAMEX> and Northeastern regions -- were largely responsible for stopping the narrowing trend. </s>
<s> Construction pacts settled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.9%</NUMEX> increases in the first contract year and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.1%</NUMEX> annually. </s>
<s> All other industries surveyed last year, including the automobile, food store and steel industries, averaged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.1%</NUMEX> increases in the first contract year and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.9%</NUMEX> annually. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> About two million workers were covered by agreements reached last year. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880311-0130 </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Attendants Snub Airline's Contract Changes </HL>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> NWA LABOR </CO>
<IN> AIR </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ST. PAUL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX> flight attendants union said new wage and work rules the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NWA Inc.</ENAMEX> unit has proposed are "unacceptable," and renewed a strike threat. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Seeking to end a yearlong stalemate with the union, as previously reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> it plans unilaterally to impose new contract terms on the attendants <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> Union leaders complained <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> is trying to "force a strike" and issued a statement advising passengers with reservations on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE" STATUS="OPT">Easter</TIMEX> holidays to "make other arrangements." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The union, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> chapter, invited leaders of the unions representing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> pilots and machinists to a strategy meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> have yet to win guarantees that the other unions would participate in a walkout. </s>
<s> An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Line Pilots Association</ENAMEX> spokesman said union leaders haven't decided whether to attend the meeting. </s>
<s> A spokesman for the machinists, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>'s largest union, couldn't be reached for comment. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> spokesman said management is "disappointed" by the union's threat to disrupt holiday service. </s>
<s> "We had hoped that if they didn't like the imposed (contract) policy, they would come back to bargaining table and get something better for themselves," he said. </s>
<s> The attendants union also called on the company's board to replace Chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven G. Rothmeier</ENAMEX> with "competent management." </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880316-0101 </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> to Create Grievance Process For Non-Union Staff </HL>
<AUTHOR> Jacob M. Schlesinger (WSJ Staff) </AUTHOR>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> C LABOR </CO>
<IN> AUT </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ROCHESTER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Corp.</ENAMEX> this year will take the highly unusual step of setting up a formal grievance procedure for its non-union white-collar employees. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "We understand that (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s) dramatic restructuring . . . will inevitably lead many employees to question management's decisions and actions," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony P. St. John</ENAMEX>, vice president for human resources of the auto maker's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Motors</ENAMEX> subsidiary, said in a speech at Oakland University here yesterday. </s>
<s> "Employees may not feel that they are being treated fairly." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> To "strengthen management's credibility," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St. John</ENAMEX> added, the company will set up an "alternative disputes resolution" system similar to a traditional union grievance procedure. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "For the first time these employees will be guaranteed a formal and impartial internal mechanism to resolve discipline, discharge, and employment opportunity disputes," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St. John</ENAMEX> said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The process will have several steps, concluding with final arbitration handled by a neutral third party. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s move apparently was inspired by the turmoil created by its current cost-cutting and restructuring, forces which are transforming many industrial companies. </s>
<s> The auto maker is significantly changing wage and benefit plans, and is trying to slash its white-collar rolls, particularly in the wake of its acquisition last year of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Motors Corp.</ENAMEX> </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> has about 31,000 white-collar employees in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>, up sharply from roughly 21,000 in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> Some analysts speculated the move is designed to stave off further union organizing in the white-collar ranks. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Several management consultants said a formal grievance procedure with third-party arbitration was common for government employees, but they had never heard of such a policy for non-union employees at a major private company. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "It has the potential of undermining supervisory and management responsibility and authority," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerrold Bratkovich</ENAMEX>, a vice president in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> office of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hay Group</ENAMEX>, a management consulting firm. </s>
<s> "That's one of the main reasons employers don't want to have unionization." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> spokesman said the company had studied "a couple" of other companies that had arbitration for nonunion employees, but he couldn't recall which companies. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A more common business approach is the "open-door" policy such as that at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Business Machines Corp.</ENAMEX>, where "any employee who has a problem which has not been resolved to satisfaction . . . can bring the complaint to the attention of higher management," said an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> spokesman. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "If the employee is still not satisfied, the problem can be reviewed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> chief executive officer," the spokesman added. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> will implement its system later this year. </s>
<s> The details haven't yet been worked out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> According to a slide used in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St. John</ENAMEX>'s presentation, the policy would cover all "professional, administrative, management and executive employees." </s>
<s> It would also have a four-step grievance process, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX>-represented workers have. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880505-0157 </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> Doubts He'll Sign An Arms Pact at Summit </HL>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> FREST </CO>
<IN> NUK ARO </IN>
<G> EXE </G>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CHICAGO</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> acknowledged that there is little chance he and Soviet leader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX> will sign a strategic arms agreement at their summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX> later this month. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> In answering questions from members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">National Strategy Forum</ENAMEX> here, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> said it is "doubtful" that a strategic arms reduction, or START, treaty could be wrapped up in time. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> aides have been saying for weeks that there are far too many disagreements remaining for a treaty to be wrapped up, but Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s remarks represented his bluntest public assessment so far. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> said that both he and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> hope that an agreement eliminating intermediate-range nuclear missiles, signed at a summit meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, will be ratified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX> summit. </s>
<s> But then he added: "Our desire that we would be able to sign a START treaty at this <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX> summit, as we did the other one at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> summit, may not happen." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> insisted that if such a treaty is ever completed, it would have to produce "parity" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> and Soviet strategic arsenals. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880516-0071 </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Mediator Says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> Negotiations Are Progressing and Near Critical Stage </HL>
<AUTHOR> Paulette Thomas (WSJ Staff) </AUTHOR>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> TEX LABOR GOVMT </CO>
<IN> AIR </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> After months of quiet and productive meetings, negotiators in the bitter labor battle at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Airlines</ENAMEX> are approaching a critical phase in the talks, a federal mediator said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Bickford</ENAMEX>, who has been supervising the talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miami</ENAMEX>, since last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>, said that representatives of the company and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Association of Machinists</ENAMEX> have been meeting almost daily since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and have resolved hundreds of differences. </s>
<s> "We are down to the point that within a short time we will be coming to terms with the gut issues," he said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bickford</ENAMEX>'s comments are the first indication that progress has occurred in the high-stakes, 16-month confrontation over labor costs. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>, a unit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air Corp.</ENAMEX>, is seeking steep wage cuts from its roughly 10,000 machinists and baggage handlers as part of a plan to restore the ailing carrier to profitability, and it has shrunk its capacity about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX> in the past year while seeking the cost concessions. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> In an interview, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bickford</ENAMEX> acknowledged that the ever-growing clamor of public demonstrations, letter-writing campaigns and political lobbying have heightened antagonism at the bargaining table. </s>
<s> "Litigation, charges, counter-charges -- I'm used to that," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bickford</ENAMEX>, an 18-year mediation veteran. </s>
<s> "But the extent to which it has gone in this case is unparalleled. </s>
<s> I have never faced anything like it." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Nevertheless, "We are still talking," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bickford</ENAMEX> asserted, "and have been every day since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 26th of January</TIMEX>, with the exception of three periods totaling 10 days." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bickford</ENAMEX> expressed anger at the growing perception that the mediation process was fruitless and futile. </s>
<s> Last week, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Martinez</ENAMEX> issued a news release saying that "mediation has reached a stalemate and both sides should be allowed to return to the bargaining table." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> And for their part, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> officials continue to lobby for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Mediation Board</ENAMEX> to impose a deadline on the talks, without which management contends an agreement on a wage-concession package is all but impossible. </s>
<s> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> labor law applying to airlines, the mediator may declare an impasse and begin a 30-day countdown, after which management may unilaterally impose its last contract offer and the union is free to strike. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "I don't believe there is any prospect of getting a negotiated settlement," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Bakes</ENAMEX>, president and chief executive officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>, "until there is a firm date when the existing contract comes to an end." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The union says that it is bargaining seriously and that each side has made concessions. </s>
<s> A settlement through mediation is possible, "absolutely," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bryan</ENAMEX>, head of the machinists' union at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> "I have never called a strike at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>," he said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machinists</ENAMEX> union -- as well as the pilot and flight attendant unions at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>, from whom management will also seek concessions in the coming months -- is anxious to avoid a strike. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> has made elaborate preparations to keep the airline flying with non-union workers. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Even as talks continue under Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bickford</ENAMEX>, neither side shows any sign of relenting in public. </s>
<s> Last week, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> ran newspaper advertising featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Borman</ENAMEX>, the former astronaut and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> president, saying the federal investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air</ENAMEX> resulted from a union "whisper campaign" alleging the airline is unsafe. </s>
<s> A week earlier, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machinist</ENAMEX> and pilot unions, accusing them of a criminal conspiracy to drive down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air</ENAMEX>'s stock price. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air</ENAMEX> are also urging employees and shareholders to write their members of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> demanding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Mediation Board</ENAMEX> begin the 30-day countdown in the talks. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, about 3,000 union members took part in a lunch-time demonstration in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miami</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air</ENAMEX> and Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bickford</ENAMEX> said he was so upset by the level and tenor of the recent clamor, that the talks were moved for a period in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miami</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> is based, to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston</ENAMEX>, where he hoped things would be quieter. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880614-0077 </DOCNO>
<HL> Early Aluminum Talks Set By Steel Union, 2 Firms </HL>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> LABOR AA RLM </CO>
<IN> MIN </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ST. LOUIS</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The United Steelworkers</ENAMEX> union agreed yesterday to open early contract talks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX> with the nation's two biggest aluminum makers. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Local presidents, meeting here, voted to begin the early bargaining in an effort to roll back concessions granted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> The current pacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aluminum Co.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds Metals Co.</ENAMEX> expire next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>, and any new accord would supersede that one. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "When we negotiated the current contracts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, our members made sacrifices to help the companies over hard times," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Becker</ENAMEX>, the union's chief negotiator. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Since then, though, the aluminum industry has staged a strong recovery, and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becker</ENAMEX> said union members expect to "share in those gains and recover the sacrifices they made." </s>
<s> Under normal circumstances, bargaining wouldn't have begun until next year. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcoa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Va.</ENAMEX>, have agreed to the early talks. </s>
<s> The union's action follows a similar decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aluminum, Brick and Glass Workers</ENAMEX> union, which bargains in concert with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steelworkers</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Combined, the two unions represent about 21,000 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alcoa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX> employees. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880729-0142 </DOCNO>
<HL> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> Appears to Back Off a Price War As Output Sags, Quota Violator Reforms </HL>
<AUTHOR> James Tanner (WSJ Staff) </AUTHOR>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> MDEST </CO>
<IN> PET MON </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
</p>
<p>
<s> After recent major price declines because of a sharp rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> production, total cartel output has now dropped as much as one million barrels a day -- from the year's peak of 20 million barrels a day early this month. </s>
<s> And there are new indications that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s most notable quota violator, might soon cut its own output below a targeted 1.5 million barrels a day because of pressure from others in the cartel, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX> aren't making any promises publicly. </s>
<s> But its government did offer conciliatory gestures to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> yesterday. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The gestures followed the arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Abu Dhabi</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s new secretary-general, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subroto</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subroto</ENAMEX> delivered a letter to Sheik <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zayed Al Nahyyan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' ruler, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rilwanu Lukman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s oil minister and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s president, voicing concern over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' recent renunciation of its assigned quota of 948,000 barrels a day. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The chief conciliatory note at the round of talks with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subroto</ENAMEX> came from Sheik <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zayed</ENAMEX>, who "reaffirmed" the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s "unity and cohesion." </s>
<s> According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' official news agency, the ruler also noted that his country "has always been at the forefront for boosting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> decisions and supporting the stability of the market." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The news agency report didn't mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' production level. </s>
<s> But senior oil officials in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX> were quoted by Dow Jones International Petroleum Report yesterday as saying that while the government isn't backing down on its demand for a higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> quota, current production is well under the target. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Industry estimates generally place the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' current production at between 1.2 million and 1.5 million barrels a day. </s>
<s> Until recently, such excess output by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX> would have been ignored. </s>
<s> But it became an issue for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> -- as well as for the world oil markets -- last month, when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' officials went public with their intent to renounce their quota. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> That not only focused new attention on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> output, which had begun climbing in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, as previously reported, but it also raised concern among other exporters. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> With <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> also excluded from the system as a result of fallout from its war with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iran</ENAMEX>, "they are afraid that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">UAE</ENAMEX> continues outside there will be no control over the others," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bahman Karbassioun</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vienna</ENAMEX>-based consultant on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> affairs. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> In addition to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subroto</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Abu Dhabi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s price-monitoring committee of five leading oil ministers also is tentatively scheduled to meet next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lausanne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, to address the problem of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emirates</ENAMEX>' unilateral quota decision, and to review world oil prices. </s>
<s> But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s headquarters yesterday still declined to confirm details of the meeting. </s>
<s> "It's tentative because it depends on the outcome of the talks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">UAE</ENAMEX>," said an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> spokesman. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Meanwhile, total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> output has dropped as much as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> after the recent run-up -- with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, the cartel's biggest producer, pacing the declines. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PetroLogistics Ltd.</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Geneva</ENAMEX>-based consulting firm that closely monitors <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> output, estimates production for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> had averaged just over 19 million barrels a day after reaching 20 million barrels a day in the first week of the month. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> That's in line with demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX> oil for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX>, according to a current report on world oil markets by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles L. McSpadden</ENAMEX>, manager of petroleum analysis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio M. Szabo</ENAMEX>, manager of petroleum planning, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonner & Moore Market Consultants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Houston</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> "The 19 million barrels a day is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPEC</ENAMEX>'s comfort zone," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Szabo</ENAMEX>. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880810-0021 </DOCNO>
<HL> Forest Products Firms Tentatively Agree On Pact in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> </HL>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> LABOR </CO>
<IN> PUL </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">VANCOUVER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> A group of large <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX> forest products companies has reached a tentative, three-year labor contract with about 18,000 members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IWA-Canada</ENAMEX> union, a spokesman for the companies said. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The settlement involves about 80 companies, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacMillan Bloedel Ltd.</ENAMEX> and other large integrated forest products concerns with operations on the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> The companies negotiate jointly through a bargaining agent called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest Industrial Relations Ltd.</ENAMEX> </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A spokesman for the bargaining agent said the settlement is retroactive to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15</TIMEX> and provides for a pay increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">85 Canadian cents</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70.2 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">US</ENAMEX> cents</NUMEX>) in the first year and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.5%</NUMEX> in each of the second and third years, on a base rate of about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14.80 Canadian dollars</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">US</ENAMEX>$12.23</NUMEX>) an hour. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The pay terms are similar to those accepted recently by members of two pulp and paper unions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>, the spokesman said. </s>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IWA-Canada</ENAMEX> settlement involves workers in sawmills, logging operations and wood manufacturing, and the contract remains subject to ratification by the union members. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The union is still negotiating with two smaller regional employer bargaining groups in the interior of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> The continuing negotiations affect about 8,000 to 10,000 union members. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 880922-0057 </DOCNO>
<HL> Your Money Matters: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> Says Brokers Can't Insist on Arbitration </HL>
<AUTHOR> Christi Harlan (WSJ Staff) </AUTHOR>
<SO> </SO>
<IN> SCR </IN>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, in a move that may be repeated in a number of states, will eliminate mandatory arbitration in disputes between brokers and investors. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A new regulation, scheduled to take effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>, will require brokers to advise customers of their constitutional right to take disputes to court. </s>
<s> And brokers can't refuse to do business with an investor who declines to sign a statement agreeing to settle disputes through arbitration. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The securities industry has favored arbitration because it keeps brokers and dealers out of court. </s>
<s> But consumer advocates say customers sometimes unwittingly sign away their right to sue. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "We don't necessarily have a beef with the arbitration process," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Meehan</ENAMEX>, deputy secretary of state in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> "We just think the consumers ought to have a choice." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is the first of what may be several states to bar mandatory arbitration. </s>
<s> According to a survey by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Securities Administrators Association</ENAMEX>, which comprises securities regulators in the 50 states, a dozen or more states in the next six months expect to consider rules banning forced arbitration. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The securities administrators have a laundry list of complaints against mandatory arbitration. </s>
<s> "The panels (of arbitrators) are stacked in favor of the industry, the proceedings are not public and there are no written decisions," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Stapf</ENAMEX>, director of consumer education for the administrators' association. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mandatory arbitration agreements have proliferated since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1987</TIMEX> that brokers could require that their customers sign them. </s>
<s> The most common agreements require customers who believe their brokers have defrauded them to submit to arbitration instead of filing a lawsuit. </s>
<s> Because of rules requiring abbreviated evidence and arguments, arbitration is generally faster than going to court. </s>
<s> And the losing side has no route for appeal -- the arbitrator's decision is final. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The popularity of the agreements among brokers was cemented after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> market crash. </s>
<s> As a result of previously signed agreements, hundreds of investors were forced to file arbitration claims, and brokers avoided time-consuming and expensive lawsuits. </s>
<s> But the securities administrators' association said most of the 15,000 calls to its post-crash hotline were complaints about forced arbitration. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mandatory arbitration agreements are most commonly required of customers buying on margin or dealing in options. </s>
<s> But the state securities regulators want to make sure that the practice doesn't spread to the smaller, less risky cash customers, hence the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> regulation. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities Industry Association</ENAMEX>, whose representatives testified against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> regulation during public hearings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, already is prepared to challenge the regulation in court. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> "What they're doing is clearly unconstitutional," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX>, general counsel for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIA</ENAMEX>. </s>
<s> "There will be a legal challenge." </s>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzpatrick</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1987</TIMEX> that states are pre-empted from taking any action against arbitration in securities cases. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling, he says, said only that brokers can require customers to sign arbitration agreements. </s>
<s> "It doesn't say arbitration agreements are OK and everyone should sign on," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> says. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 881027-0010 </DOCNO>
<HL> Technology Brief -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olin Corp.</ENAMEX>: Technology-Sharing Accord Is Signed With Italian Firm </HL>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> OLN </CO>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olin Corp.</ENAMEX> and a subsidiary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGS Thomson Microelectronics Group</ENAMEX> signed a "strategic alliance" agreement that calls for a sharing of microchip-manufacturing technology. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> A spokesman for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olin</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stamford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Conn.</ENAMEX>, said the company would share chemicals, metals and microchip interconnection, or packaging, technology with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Innovative Silicon Technology</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGS-Thomson</ENAMEX> unit. </s>
<s> The Italian microchip maker, meanwhile, would give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olin</ENAMEX> access to its production processes. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Separately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olin</ENAMEX> said it expects <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> net income to rise to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.60</NUMEX> a share from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.32</NUMEX> a share last year. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> He attributed the expected improvement to the company's recent restructuring. </s>
</p>
</TXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> 881110-0113 </DOCNO>
<HL> Who's News: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX> Creates Pricey Image for the Masses </HL>
<AUTHOR> Teri Agins (WSJ Staff) </AUTHOR>
<SO> </SO>
<CO> GIT </CO>
<IN> PRO </IN>
<DATELINE> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEW YORK</ENAMEX>  </DATELINE>
<TXT>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano Group Inc.</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haim Dabah</ENAMEX> likes to think of his company as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz Claiborne</ENAMEX> of the masses." </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz Claiborne Inc.</ENAMEX> and other high-fashion womenswear makers sell their clothes through department stores and pricey boutiques, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s market is distinctly middle American. </s>
<s> Its outlets are mass merchandisers and discount chains such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K mart Corp.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart Stores Inc.</ENAMEX> </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> But like its more glamorous competitors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> puts heavy emphasis on advertising and promotion to create a fashion image for its clothes. </s>
<s> In fact, company focus groups indicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> customers associate the brand with fashionable department stores like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Neiman-Marcus</ENAMEX> even though it's primarily sold through mass merchandisers. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> That perception has been credited to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX>, who "has a great flair for marketing and presentation," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Greenstein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> chief financial officer. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s marketing strategy seems to be paying off. </s>
<s> While much of the apparel industry is in the doldrums, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> is posting big increases in revenue and earnings. </s>
<s> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the company said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> earnings jumped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.2%</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.1 million</NUMEX> on sales of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$119.1 million</NUMEX>. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Its stock, which was priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20.50</NUMEX> a share when the company went public on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30</TIMEX>, dropped a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. </s>
<s> But analysts didn't see any significance in the drop, since it's a relatively new issue and it's thinly traded -- Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX> and his family still control <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> of the company. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman G. Fosback</ENAMEX>, editor of New Issues, an investment newsletter, notes that investors, familiar with the up-and-down cycles on Seventh Avenue, may be skeptical as to whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> can fly any higher. </s>
<s> "One wonders how long can they go on like this," he says. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bentonville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ark.</ENAMEX>, says that in the two years it has carried the brand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> has grown to become one of its top apparel resources, selling "better than others in the same price range." </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WalMart</ENAMEX> attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s success to its high-profile marketing techniques and close monitoring of sales trends. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX> "firmly believes that after you sell to the retailer, it's just the beginning," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenstein</ENAMEX> says. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> For example, discount stores are strictly self-service, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> attaches big, colored tags on clothes to show customers how they can fashionably pair tops and bottoms, a tactic that also induces multiple sales. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX>, a vivacious salesman, compares himself to "a baseball player coming to work." </s>
<s> He relishes cooking up new marketing strategies, listing such projects as mail-in rebates and gift certificates with a purchase. </s>
<s> In the past three years, the company also held a nationwide "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> Girl" model-search contest. </s>
<s> At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Bradlees</ENAMEX> stores, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> recently sponsored a sales contest for department managers with prizes like trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Club Med</ENAMEX> and color televisions. </s>
<s> The result: sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> clothes were up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">180%</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION" STATUS="OPT">Bradlees</ENAMEX> in one month. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> As part of his hectic day, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX> touches base with his brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>, the company's vice chairman, who oversees <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s production at its factories in 31 countries, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra</ENAMEX>, president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s children's wear division. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX>, whose father <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> -- chairman of the company -- founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> 17 years ago after emigrating from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Israel</ENAMEX>, says a major reason the company sells through mass merchandisers is because it's easier to keep costs down. </s>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s staple products -- tops and bottoms for women that sell for around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> -- don't have "major fashion risks," he says. </s>
<s> That means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> can commit to styles months ahead of when they're needed and keep its factory contractors operating in slack periods. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> also has the luxury of always shipping its goods by sea instead of air. </s>
<s> Any sudden fashion shift won't reach the mass market until a season or two later, anyway. </s>
<s> The cost savings can be passed on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s retailers, allowing the company, for example, to keep the wholesale price of its jeans at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> when "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> is at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.75</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.50</NUMEX>," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX> says. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> The company works to keep its costs down in other areas, too. </s>
<s> Two years ago, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX> shifted the responsibility for the company's extensive print and television advertising to an in-house staff, enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> to get more mileage from its annual <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> advertising budget. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> has pulled off a clever illusion with its advertising. </s>
<s> The campaign gives its clothes a youthful and trendy image to lure consumers into the store. </s>
<s> But most of the clothes are actually cut to fit more mature bodies. </s>
<s> Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s fans are aging baby boomers, and some of the brand's top sellers are maternity clothes and jeans for larger-sized women. </s>
</p>
<p>
<s> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dabah</ENAMEX>'s expansion plans include opening more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX> retail outlets; there are currently 35. </s>
<s> Capitalizing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gitano</ENAMEX>'s fashion image, the company also is rolling out a more expensive brand. </s>
